PHILIP PRATER

Software Engineer

CONTACT ME AT:

Mobile: 503-896-0592 Email: pprater92@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/Blergborg Website: https://github.com/Blergborg

PROFILE

Software Engineer with a background in physical sciences, I am looking to start my career in software after going back to school for a career change. Over the last 2 years, I've taken the time to gain new programming skills not covered in my formal education.

EDUCATION

CS Certificate | Portland State University Years Attended: 9/2017 - 6/2019

B.S. Chemistry | Oregon State University Years Attended: 9/2011 - 12/2015 Minor: Business and Entrepreneurship Graduated Cum Laude

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- Python
- Kotlin/Java
- TypeScript
- C++/C
- Dart/Flutter
- NoSQL
- SQL
- HTML/CSS

TOOLS & FRAMEWORKS

- Git/GitHub
- Android Studio
- Android Jetpack
- · React.js
- Node.js/Express.js
- Jest/Mocha
- Postman
- Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib
- Flack
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- Firebase
- · Material UI
- Heroku

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Brew Notes App

Android app made with Flutter/Dart to help home-brewers keep organized notes on their phone. A user keeps track of different recipes (beer, cider, etc.) and can take notes on how different attempts at each recipe went, or log data such as daily temperature readings.

https://github.com/Blergborg/brew_notes

Spellbook App

Single page React/Typescript app meant to help players better manage their spells for playing 5th edition Dungeons and Dragons. Users set their class and level from a form, then the app queries a REST API and presents what spells can be used and some class-specific resources. Deployed on Heroku.

https://spellbook-5.herokuapp.com/

Choose Your Own Adventure Game

Python command line game to refresh on various basics and the language itself. Reads a simple story from a .json file, loads an array of 'rooms' that have a description and options for a player, each option tells the player what happens as a result of being picked and provides the location of the next 'room' the player will move to as a result. The player also has an inventory that is used to determine if certain options are available in a room.

https://github.com/Blergborg/CYOA

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer

Independent | Septemember 2021-Present

Shop Hand

Reimers & Jolivette Inc. | June 2011-Present

Independent Contractor

Amorphyx Inc. | July 2014-May 2015

Undergrad Research Assistant

Loveland Lab Group OSU | April 2013-June 2013

-Testing Resolution of the Fission Time Projection Chamber at Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory